Guide to the Nell Irvin Painter Papers, 1793-2021 and undated, bulk 1876-2007 RL.00990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Research Series, 1793, 1835-2007 and undated, bulk 1876-2004, 66 boxes
  - Writings by Others Subseries, 1859-2007 and undated, bulk 1972-1996, 11 boxes
    - McNeil, Genna Rae, 1978-1979 and undated, 2 folders (Box 150)
    - McNeil, Genna Rae and Jesse Jai McNeil, 1978 and undated, 2 folders (Box 150)
    - Mendenhall, Marjorie: Southern Women of a 'Lost Generation,' 1934 (Box 150)
    - Millette, James, et al: Freedom Road, 1988 (Box 150)
    - Mitchell, Lee: On Ellen Glasgow's Uncolored Souls, circa 1989 (Box 150)
    - Mitchell, Louis 1983, 4 writings (Box 150)
    - Moody, JoAnn: Tenure and Diversity: Some Different Voices, 2000 (Box 150)
    - Moody, Joycelyn: Doublespeak and Disruption in the Memoir of Old Elizabeth, 1991 (Box 150)
    - Morrison, Toni: disturbing nurses and the kindness of sharks, Playing in the Dark, 1992 (Box 150)
    - Morton, Eric: "Race and Racism in the Works of David Hume," Journal of African Philosophy, 2002 (Box 262)
    - unspecified (Box 150)
    - Mottl, Tahi Lani: The Sociological Analysis of 'Oral Histories,' 1982 (Box 150)
    - Naison, Mark: 1973-1976 and undated, 4 writings (Box 150)
    - Nickel, James: 1990 and undated, 2 writings (Box 150)
    - Nieli, Russell: The Disintegration of the Black Lower Class Family, undated (Box 150)
    - Norton, Mary Beth: Gender, Society, and Politics in 17th-Century US, 1987 (Box 151)
    - O'Brien, Sharon: Feminist Theory and Literary Biography, 1992 (Box 151)
    - O'Malley, Michael: "Specie and Species: Race and the Money Question in Nineteenth-Century America," 1994 (Box 262)
    - Palmer, Colin: African Slave Trade: The Cruelest Commerce, National Geographic, 1992 (Box 151)
    - Palmer, Stacy E.: In the Fishbowl: When Blacks Work at Predominantly White Colleges, 1983 (Box 151)
    - Peacock, James: The Narrated Self, 1989 (Box 151)
    - Peiss, Kathy: Making Faces: The Cosmetics Industry and the Cultural Construction of Gender..., 1990 (Box 151)
    - Pemberton, Gayle: Do He Have Your Number, Mr. Jeffrey? The Threepenny Review, 1990 (Box 151)
    - Podair, Jerald E.: Ocean-Hill-Brownsville, 1964-1973, 1993 (Box 151)
    - Quarles, Benjamin: Frederick Douglass and the Women's Rights Movement, 1993 (Box 151)
    - Rampersad, Arnold: "Biography, Autobiography, and Afro-American Culture," The Yale Review, 1983 (Box 262)
    - box 151 (Box 151)
    - Reefe, Thomas Q.: The Biggest Game of All: Gambling in Traditional Africa, 1983 (Box 151)
    - Reid, Donald: Guillaume Verdier et le Syndicalisme Revolutionnaire aux Usines de Decazeville (1917-1920), 1984 (Box 151)
    - Robinson, Armstead L.: What Causes the Roar of Their Fall? War, Internal Security,... Confederate States of America, 1989 (Box 151)
    - Robinson, Cedric: Richard Wright: Marxism and the Petite-bourgeoisie, circa 1980 (Box 151)
    - Rosengarten, Theodore, 1972, 1975, 1986, 3 writings (Box 151)
    - Ross, Caleb: The Destruction of Louisville, 1886 (Box 151)
    - Rothenberg, Randall: The Idea Monger, Esquire, 1996 (Box 151)
    - Rouille, Andre and Bernard Marbot: Le Corps et Son Image, 1986 (Box 151)
    - Sahlins, Marshall: Culture and Practical Reason, 1976 (Box 151)
    - Sanders, Mark: Theorizing the Collaborative Self, 1991 (Box 151)
    - Sarbin, Theo.: Stevenson College, UCSC 95064, 1981, 1987, and 1989 (Box 151)
    - Science and Factual, 2007 (Box 262)
    - box 151 (Box 151)
    - Schofield, Ann, 1990, 3 writings (Box 151)
    - Schwalm, Leslie: Bibliography, 1995 (Box 151)
    - Schwartz, Joan M.: The 'Little Wanzer,' 1986 (Box 151)
    - Self-Deception, 1988 (Box 151)
    - Seraile, William: Susan McKinney Steward: New York State's First African-American Woman Physician, 1985; Henrietta Vinton Davis and the Garvey Movement, 1983 (Box 151)
    - Sharkey, Robert P.: Money, Class, and Party: An Economic Study of Civil War and Reconstruction, 1959, and Painter's notes on greenbackism, undated (Box 151)
    - Shell, Robert: Tender Ties: Women and the Slave Housegold, 1652-1834, 1992 (Box 151)
    - Shlomowitz, Ralph: 'Bound' or 'Free'? Black Labor in Cotton and Sugarcane Farming, 1865-1880, 1984 (Box 151)
    - Silvestrini, Blanca G.: Women and Resistance:... Caribbean History, 1989 (Box 151)
    - Sklar, Kathryn Kish: Florence Kelley and the Integration of 'Women's Sphere' into American Politics..., 1986 (Box 151)
    - Solomon, Mark: Communist Theory and 'Negro Work,' 1977 (Box 151)
    - Spady, James G.: Negritude, PanBanegritude, and the Diopian Philosophy of African History, 1972 (Box 151)
    - Spira, S.F.: Daguerreotypes as a Selling Tool, 1979 (Box 151)
    - Stanley, Liz, 1987, 1992, 2 writings (Box 151)
    - Stansell, Christine: Love and Greenwich Village: Art, Sex, and Politics in Radical America 1980-1919, circa 1990 (Box 151)
    - Stark, Elizabeth: on incest, 1984 (Box 151)
    - Stoler, Ann: Sexual Affronts and Racial Frontiers: European Identities and the Cultural Politics of Exclusion in Colonial Southeast Asia, 1992 (Box 151)
    - Stone, Alfred Holt: Studies in the American Race Problem, 1908 (Box 151)
    - Stowe, Steven M.: City, Country, and the Feminine Voice, Intellectual Life in Antebellum Charleston, 1986 (Box 152)
    - Swan, Jim: Mater and Nannie: Freud's 2 Mothers, 1974 (Box 152)
    - Szilard, Leo: "Are We on the Road to War?" 1961 (Box 262)
    - Taves, Ann: Spiritual Purity and Sexual Shame: Religious Themes in the Writings of Harriet Jacobs, Church History, 1987 (Box 152)
    - Taylor, Ula: Amy Jacques-Garvey: Community Feminist, undated (Box 152)
    - Taylor, Theman Ray: Cyril Briggs and the African Blood Brotherhood, undated (Box 152)
    - Terbor-Penn, Rosalyn: Nineteenth Century Black Women and Woman Suffrage, 1977 (Box 152)
    - Thompson, Becky: Hunger So Wide and So Deep, 1993 (Box 152)
    - Thompson, Becky: Making A Way Outa No Way, 1993 (Box 152)
    - Thompson, Mindy: The National Negro Labor Council: A History, 1978 (Box 152)
    - Thompson, P.S.: The Study and Teaching of American History in the Universities in South Africa in the 1980s, undated (Box 152)
    - Thornhill, Randy, undated, 20 writings; 2 Folders (Box 152)
    - Thorpe, Earl E.: The Meier-Rudwick Book on Black Historians, 1986 (Box 152)
    - Toews, John E.: Freud and Dora Historicized, undated (Box 152)
    - Trachtenberg, Alan: "Comment, 'Remembering Slavery,'" SHA, 1994 (Box 262)
    - box 152 (Box 152)
    - Turner, Dr. William H. and Edward R. Cabbel: Blacks in Appalachia: Notes on an 'Invisible' People, 1983 (Box 152)
    - Tuttle, William M., Jr.: The Birth of an Industry: The Synthetic Rubber 'Mess'..., 1981 (Box 152)
    - Valenti, Patricia Dunlavy: Sophia Peabody Hawthorne, Women Writing Women's Lives, 1996 (Box 152)
    - Von Alstyne, Abby: Freedmen's Savings and Trust Company, undated (Box 152)
    - Walker, Alice: Lulls, In Search of Our Mothers' Gardens, 1983 (Box 152)
    - Walters, Ronald G.: Erotic South, 1973 (Box 152)
    - Weber, Eugen: Peasants into Frenchmen.. ., 1976 (Box 152)
    - Welling, William: Photography in America:... 1839-1900, 1978 (Box 152)
    - White, Deborah: "Telling Histories: Black Women in the Ivory Tower," undated (Box 262)
    - unspecified (Box 152)
    - White, Deborah, undated (Box 152)
    - Wiener, Jon: Compromised Positions, 1993 (Box 152)
    - Wilkinson, Doris Y.: The Doll Exhibit, 1987 (Box 152)
    - Wilsher, Ann: Photography in Literature, 1978 (Box 152)
    - Wilson, Francille R.: Black Labor History in the Twenties, undated (Box 152)
    - Winship, Michael: 'The Greatest Book of Its Kind': A Publishing History of Uncle Tom's Cabin, 1999 (Box 152)
    - Wood, Peter H.: The Pardoner's Tale: The Personal Theme of 'Domestic Tranquility' in Gerald Ford's Pardon of Richard Nixon, 1987 (Box 152)
    - Woodman, Harold D.
      - The Economic and Social History of Blacks in the Post-Emancipation South, 1982 (Box 152)
      - Postbellum Social Change and its Effects on Marketing the South's Cotton Crop, 1982 (Box 152)
      - Post-Civil War Southern Agriculture and the Law, 1979 (Box 152)
      - Sequel to Slavery: The New History Views the Postbellum South, 1977 (Box 152)
    - Wright, Richard: Uncle Tom's Children, 1965 (Box 152)
    - Wright, Roberta Hughes: material on burial customs, 1994 (Box 152)
    - Zboray, Ronald J.: Reading and the World of Goods in Antebellum New England, 1993 (Box 152)
- Teaching Materials, 1969-2004 and undated, bulk 1974-2000, 28 boxes
  Documents Painter's work with students and academic colleagues at Harvard University, Wellesley College, the Universities of Pennsylvania and North Carolina, Hunter College, and Princeton University. Arranged in two subseries, Courses and Academic Files.
  - Courses Subseries, 1971-2004 and undated, bulk 1974-1996, 14 boxes
    Contains syllabi, reading lists, class lectures, notes, class readings, notes, and some correspondence and miscellaneous other materials that Painter produced and gathered for courses she taught at Wellesley College, the Universities of Pennsylvania and North Carolina, Hunter College, and Princeton University. Copies of class readings include both printed material and typescripts transcribed from archival materials and microfilm; some contain Painter's notes and interpretations in margins or attached pages. Arranged in chronological order by year.
    - 1971-1974 (Box 153)
      - History 332 (Box 153)
    - 1971-1990
      - Various courses, syllabi and notes (Box 153)
    - 1972
      - History 315, "The Social History of Black Americans, 1820-1919," Fall (Box 153)
    - 1972-1973
      - History 161 (Box 153)
    - 1972-1974
      - History 315, "The Social History of Black Americans, 1820-1919" and History 376, "Survey of Afro-American History" (Box 153)
    - 1974
      - History 161, "American Political History Since 1920," Spring (Box 153)
      - History 200, "Black Women," Fall (Box 153)
      - History 376, "Survey of Afro-American History," Fall (Box 153)
      - History 376, "Survey of Afro-American History", 3 folders (Box 153)
    - circa 1974-1975
      - History 161, 1920s lecture (Box 153)
    - 1975
      - History 376, "Survey of Afro-American History," Spring (Box 153)
      - History 200, "Afro-American History Through Autobiography," Fall (Box 153)
      - Lecture Notes on Frederick Douglass (Box 153)
      - History 366, "The Age of Booker T. Washington," Fall, 2 folders (Box 154)
      - History 200 and History 376, "Survey of Afro-American History" (Box 154)
      - History 299, "Independent Study" and History 366, "The Age of Booker T. Washington" (Box 154)
    - 1975-1976
      - History 376, "Introduction to Afro-American Studies" and History 566, "The Turn of the Century" (Box 154)
    - 1975-1978
      - History courses: notes and readings (Box 154)
    - 1976
      - History 60, "Race Relations," Apr. (Box 154)
      - History 200, "Afro-American Women Since 1865," Spring, 2 folders (Box 154)
      - History 376, "Survey of Afro-American History, 1879 to the Present," Spring, 3 folders (Box 154)
      - History 566, "The Turn of the Century," Spring (Box 154)
      - History 161, "The Turn of The Century--Class and Race," Fall (Box 154)
    - 1977
      - History 100, "CPUSA," Fall, 2 folders (Box 154)
      - History 100 and History 566, Fall 1977 reading lists (Box 155)
      - History 566, "The Turn of the Century," Fall, 2 folders (Box 155)
    - 1977-1978
      - History 566, "Turn of the Century" (Box 155)
    - 1977-1980
      - History 165, "Survey of Afro-American History"; History 166, "Survey of Afro-American History from 1895 to the Present"; History 290, "The Turn of the Century"; and History 566, "The Turn of the Century" (Box 155)
    - 1978
      - History 200, "20th c. American History Through Autobiography," Spring (Box 155)
      - History 566, "The Turn of the Century," Spring (Box 155)
      - History 566, "Turn of the Century Remedies," Spring (Box 155)
      - History 566, "Jack London's The Iron Heel" and notes, circa 1978 (Box 155)
    - 1979
      - Lecture Notes on Philip Curtain, Africa Remembered (Box 155)
      - Printed material (Box 155)
    - 1980
      - History 75, "American Autobiographies," Fall (Box 155)
      - History 166, "Survey of Afro-American History from 1895 to the Present," Spring, 2 folders (Box 156)
      - History 290, "Readings in Afro-American History," Fall (Box 156)
    - 1980-1987
      - History 22H, History 75, "20th c. Southern Autobiographies"; History 166, "Survey of Afro-American History from 1895 to the Present"; and History 265, "Readings in Afro-American History" (Box 156)
    - 1981
      - History 22, Spring (Box 156)
      - History 166 lectures," Survey of Afro-American History from 1895 to the Present," Spring (Box 156)
      - History 75, Fall (Box 156)
      - American Studies 60, "Democracy" (Box 156)
      - "Becoming American" (Box 156)
    - 1981-1982
      - History 22H (Box 156)
    - 1981-1984
      - History 22, "Views of Theodore Roosevelt" (Box 156)
    - 1982 (Box 157)
      - History 22H, Spring, 3 folders (Box 157)
      - Women's Studies 50, Mar. (Box 157)
      - Independent Study, Spring (Box 157)
    - 1983
      - History 93, "Becoming American," Fall, 2 folders (Box 157)
      - History 265, "Recent Writing in Afro-American History" and bibliography for Encyclopedia Americana, Fall (Box 157)
    - 1983-1985
      - History 90, "Industrialization and Democracy: The United States, 1886-1919"; History 200; and History 300,"Introductory Seminar, American History" (Box 157)
    - 1984
      - History 22, "Survey of the History of the United States from 1865 to the Present," Spring, 2 folders (Box 157)
      - History 22-7, "Survey of the History of the United States from 1865 to the Present," midterm exam, Feb. 14 (Box 157)
      - Afro-American History 65, "Class, Gender, and Region in Afro-American History Today," Fall (Box 157)
      - History 22, "Survey of the History of the United States from 1865 to the Present," final (Box 157)
    - 1984-1985
      - History 200, "Research Methods Seminar"; History 209, "Colloquium in U.S. History to 1865" (Professors William Barney and John Nelson); History 300 and 330,"Seminar on the American Revolution" (Professor Higginbotham), 2 folders (Box 157)
      - History courses (Box 157)
    - 1985
      - History 22, Spring, Folder 1 of 5 (Box 157)
      - History 22, Spring, Folders 2-5 of 5 (Box 158)
      - History 22 (Box 158)
      - History 341, "The South Since 1865," Fall (Box 158)
      - "Class, Gender, and Race in Afro-American History," Fall, 2 folders (Box 158)
    - 1985-1986
      - Lecture Notes on Various Topics (Box 158)
    - 1986
      - History 341, "The South Since 1865," Spring, 4 folders (Box 158)
      - History 94, "Becoming American," Fall, Folder 1 of 3 (Box 158)
      - History 94, "Becoming American," Fall, Folders 2-3 of 3 (Box 159)
      - History 94 and History 166 exam questions, Fall (Box 159)
      - History 166, "Afro-American History Since 1865," Fall, 3 folders (Box 159)
      - History 341, "The South Since 1865," Fall, 2 folders (Box 159)
      - History 341, "The South Since 1865" (Box 159)
    - 1987
      - History 72, Spring, Folder 1 of 4 (Box 159)
      - History 72, Spring, Folders 2-4 of 4 (Box 160)
      - History 265, "Recent Writing in Afro-American History," Spring (Box 160)
      - History 72, "The United States: 1865 to the Present," Fall, 2 folders (Box 160)
      - History 72 (Box 160)
    - 1988
      - History 167, Spring, 2 folders (Box 160)
      - History 166, "Black Women in the 20th Century," Fall (Box 161)
    - 1989
      - History 381, Fall (Box 161)
      - History 581, "Woman/Women in the South," Fall, 3 folders (Box 161)
    - 1990
      - History 381, "The United States South," Spring, 2 folders (Box 161)
      - Afro-American Studies 414, "Black Women Writers," Fall (Box 161)
      - History 589, "Readings in American History: Reconstruction to World War I," Fall, 3 folders (Box 161)
      - History 781, Southern Masculinities, Folders 1-2 of 5 (Box 161)
      - History 781, Southern Masculinities, Folders 3-5 of 5 (Box 162)
      - Neely, George, Institutional Racism/Sexism in N.C. State Government (Box 162)
    - 1991
      - Afro-American Studies 201, "African-American Leadership," Apr. (Box 162)
      - Afro-American Studies 384, Spring (Box 162)
      - Afro-American Studies 311, "An Introduction to Black Women's Studies," Fall, 3 folders (Box 162)
      - Afro-American Studies 500, "The Afro-American Intellectual Tradition," Fall, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box 162)
      - Afro-American Studies 500, "The Afro-American Intellectual Tradition," Fall, Folder 3 of 3 (Box 163)
      - Afro-American Studies 501, "Introduction to the Afro-American Intellectual Tradition", 2 folders (Box 163)
    - 1991-1992
      - Afro-American Studies 500, 3 folders (Box 163)
      - Florencia E. Mellon Syllabus (History 573, University of Wisconsin-Madison) (Box 163)
    - 1992
      - History 381 (Box 163)
    - 1993
      - Afro-American Studies 311, "An Introduction to Black Women's Studies," Fall, 2 folders (Box 163)
      - History 400, David K. Shipler on Jefferson (Box 163)
      - History 581, "Gender and Sexuality in the South," Fall, 3 folders (Box 163)
    - 1993-1994
      - Afro-American Studies 311, "Introduction to Black Women's Studies" (Box 163)
    - 1994
      - History 381, "The United States South, 1865 to the Present," Spring (Box 163)
      - Students on Truth (Box 264)
      - History 4--, "Issues in Southern Identity," Spring (Box 164)
      - History 465, Paul Finkelman visit, 2 folders (Box 164)
      - Afro-American Studies 311, "Introduction to Black Women's Studies," Fall (Box 164)
      - History 774, "Social History: Race, Class, Gender, and Sexuality in the U.S.," Fall (Box 164)
    - 1994-1996
      - History 465 (Box 164)
    - 1995
      - History 381, "The United States South, 1865 to the Present," Spring, 2 folders (Box 164)
      - History 581, "Gender and Sexuality in the South," Spring, 2 folders (Box 164)
      - "Women at Work," research for courses and seminars (Box 164)
    - 1996
      - Afro-American Studies 500, Jan.-Feb. (Box 164)
      - Afro-American Studies 501, "Research Seminar in African-American Studies," Spring (Box 164)
      - Women's Studies 501, Kristin Luker Bibliography (Box 164)
      - History 574, "Social History," Spring (Box 164)
      - Women's Studies 501, "Women's Studies Graduate Proseminar," Spring, 2 folders (Box 164)
    - 1998
      - History 400, Personal Beauty: Biology or Culture, Fall (Box 164)
    - 1999
      - History 382, Whiteness in Historical Perspective (Box 164)
      - History 381, "Whiteness in Historical Perspective," (24 folders) (Box 263)
    - 2000
      - History 581, "Hermeneutics of War and Southern History" (Box 263)
    - 2002
      - History 382, "Whiteness in Historical Perspective" (Box 263)
    - 2003 (Box 164)
      - Afro-American Studies 501 (Box 164)
    - 2004
      - History 382 (Box 164)
      - Grade 11, commenting on Sojourner Truth (Box 264)
      - History 382 (Box 264)
    - Undated (Box 164)
      - Afro-American Studies 311.94, Guides to Reading (Box 164)
      - Afro-American Studies 501, "Research Seminar in Afro-American Studies" (Box 164)
      - Course readings (Box 164)
      - History 20 A (Box 164)
      - History 72, films (Box 164)
      - History 200, "Civics" (Box 164)
      - History 567, "Turn of the Century" (Box 164)
      - Reading guides (Box 164)
      - Supplementary reading list, "The Turn of the Century" (Box 164)
      - Untitled lecture outline (Box 264)
  - Academic Files Subseries, 1969-2004 and undated, bulk 1975-2000, 15 boxes
    Departmental correspondence and memoranda, meeting minutes, university and department forms and invoices, printed materials, files on students for whom Painter served as advisor or committee member, student writings, and other materials. Arranged alphabetically by institution (Harvard, Princeton, University of North Carolina, University of Pennsylvania, and Wellesley College), then chronologically within those groups. At the end of the series are several folder groups that span Painter's years in various positions, arranged alphabetically by topic. The largest of these are Applications and Job Searches, containing correspondence and other documents relating to various positions and fellowships she sought at different times; and Student Writings, containing various papers, theses, and dissertations written by Painter's students. Note that student files gathered here are mainly writings that were found unattached to correspondence and represent only a fraction of such material; the bulk of her extensive correspondence with her students, including discussion and copies of their research and writing, is in the Correspondence Series.
    - Harvard University, 1969 (Box 165)
      - 1969, Conference on Curriculum Materials for the Study of Black History (Box 165)
      - 1970, Announcements and memoranda (Box 165)
      - 1970, Luncheon (Box 165)
      - 1972-1975, Departmental correspondence and memoranda (Box 165)
    - Princeton University, 1987-2000
      - 1987-1988, Princeton, Yale, and Johns Hopkins, 2 folders (Box 165)
      - 1988, Research account (Box 165)
      - 1988-1989, Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 165)
      - 1988-1989, Senior thesis schedule (Box 165)
      - 1989 Autumn, Library chronicle (Box 165)
      - 1989, Prospectus for the Southern Institute at Princeton (Box 165)
      - 1990, Program in Afro-American Studies (Box 165)
      - 1990, Miscellaneous (Box 166)
      - 1990-1991
        - Afro-American miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 166)
        - Afro-American seminar series (Box 166)
        - Departmental guides (Box 166)
        - History department (Box 166)
        - Miscellaneous, Folder 1 of 3 (Box 166)
        - Miscellaneous, Folders 2-3 of 3 (Box 167)
        - Senior theses (Box 167)
      - 1990-1996, Syllabi, programs (Box 167)
      - 1991
        - AAS post-doctoral fellowships, Feb. (Box 167)
        - AAS personnel (Box 167)
        - Afro-American historian search (Box 167)
        - Afro-American post-doctoral fellowships (Box 167)
        - Afro-American miscellaneous, Mar., 2 folders (Box 167)
        - Afro-American Studies 201, Dr. Cornel West (Box 167)
        - Graduate students, 2 folders (Box 167)
        - History department (Box 167)
        - Miscellaneous, Feb.-Apr. (Box 167)
      - 1991-1992, Program in Women's Studies Annual Report (Box 167)
      - 1991 Dec.-1993 Mar., Graduate students (Box 168)
      - 1992
        - Graduate students, July (Box 168)
        - History department (Box 168)
        - Princeton University racial harassment survey (Box 168)
      - 1993
        - Copyright, Jan. (Box 168)
        - Excerpt from Duncan Kennedy's Sexy Dressing (Box 168)
        - Iconography of Southern History (proposed seminar) (Box 168)
        - Invoices (Box 168)
        - Jennifer Delton--general exam questions (Box 168)
      - 1993-1994
        - Committee on Diversity and Liberal Education, 2 folders (Box 168)
        - History department (Box 168)
        - University and history department files, 2 folders (Box 168)
      - 1993-1997, Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs (Box 168)
      - 1994 (Box 169)
        - Brownlee-Smithsonian multimedia (Box 169)
        - Caribbean Between Empires Symposium, Princeton (Box 169)
        - Computer access (Box 169)
        - Race Matters Conference, Princeton (Box 169)
        - Roxanne Norfleet from Rick Sobel (Box 169)
        - Use of research fund (Box 169)
        - Varieties of Anti-Modernism Colloquium, Princeton (Box 169)
        - Nellie McKay "Race, Class, and Gender" (Box 264)